Dier A. Hernandez

Peoria, AZ | (909) 676-7092 | dier.asgard@gmail.com | LinkedIn

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

I'm an accomplished Atlassian Expert Consultant with 5 years of experience contributing to outstanding success in the technology, and financial industries. Confident in the ability to effectively configure, manage, migrate, and administrate Atlassian Suit (Data Center and Cloud), including Automation, Assets, Asset Discovery, REST API, Atlassian Marketplace add-ons (ScriptRunner, JWME, Xray, Tempo, eazyBI, and more). Experienced in working with cross-functional teams in agile/scrum environments and working independently in various settings including on-site, hybrid, or full-remote. Committed to lifelong learning and contributing to team success.

KEY SKILLS

- Atlassian Expert
- Project Management
- Agile/Scrum/Kanban
- BigPicture/Tempo
- Jira Service Management
- Pvthon/Java/C++
- ScriptRunner/Automation
- Bitbucket/GitHub/Jenkins
- Migrate to Cloud
- Jira Software Confluence
- XRay/Qmetry/Zephyr
- SQL/PSQL/Oracle
- **Custom Workflow**
- ITSM/Asset Discovery
- REST Api/WebHooks

WORK EXPERIENCE

TSOFT Mexico City, MX Apr 2022 - Present

Atlassian Expert SR Consultant

- Administered, upgraded and Migrated Jira, Bitbucket and Confluence environments, ensuring lifecycle sustainability and system scalability, achieving a 30% increase in system performance and reliability.
- · Led the design and implementation of Jira Projects for various financial institudes and businesses across the US, Mexico, Spain, and Chile, focusing on custom workflows, Automations, ScriptRunner Scripts, WebHooks, RestApi, and testing, aligning IT solutions with business processes.
- Configured and managed Atlassian Marketplace add-ons, including ScriptRunner, JWME, Xray, Qmetry, Zephyr, eazyBI, BigPicture, and Tempo.
- Managed Jira screen, security, and notification schemes, enhancing team collaboration and system security.
- Provided ongoing support for Agile Kanban/Scrum teams, assisting with sprint planning, backlog management, and reporting.

Morelos Middle School

Tepatitlan de Morelos, MX

IT Support Specialist | Math & English Teacher

Aug 2019 - Apr 2022

- Managed and administered Atlassian products, including Jira Software, Jira Service Management, and Confluence, while designing and customizing workflows, issue types, and screens to optimize project management and collaboration processes.
- · Conducted routine website maintenance tasks, ensuring all content was up-to-date and resolving any technical issues promptly, resulting in a 10% decrease in customer complaints regarding website functionality.
- Established strong rapport with students by actively communicating and engaging with them during class discussions and individual sessions, creating an inclusive learning environment that led to a 20% increase in student participation and
- · Implemented innovative teaching strategies such as incorporating real-life examples and interactive activities to enhance student comprehension of math and English concepts, resulting in a 15% improvement in average test scores.

University of Guadalajara

English Teacher

Tepatitlan de Morelos, MX Aug 2017 - Aug 2019

- Established differentiated instruction techniques to cater to the unique learning needs of each student.
- Developed and executed engaging lesson plans, incorporating interactive activities and multimedia resources.
- Collaborated with a team of teachers to design and implement an intensive English language program for advanced students.

TSOFT Mexico City, MX

IT System Administrator | HPE Business Software Consultant

Sep 2014 - Aug 2016

- · Applied enterprise architecture principles to migrate legacy systems to cloud-based infrastructure, resulting in a 50% reduction in maintenance costs.
- Utilized Agile development methodologies, decreasing software defects by 30% and increasing system
- Integrated Micro Focus LoadRunner and SiteScope for continuous monitoring of over 100 servers, improving system stability and uptime by 99%.

EDUCATION

University of Guadalajara

Guadalajara, MX

B.S. Computer Engineer

University of Monterrey Tech (ITSM)

Guadalajara, MX

B.S. Electronics and Communications Engineer

CERTIFICATIONS

- Atlassian ACP-620: Jira Administration
- Atlassian DevOps Essentials
- Cloud Technical Sales & Delivery Professional

- Scrum Fundamentals Certified
- LinkedIn: DevOps, Jenkin
- Cisco: CCNA1